# Colby L. Sawyer



835 NC Hwy 343 South, Camden, NC 27921

P:(252)-333-4057

colbysawyer37@outlook.com

#### **Objective:**

A diligent professional with proven experience in software development and maintenance demonstrated by years of work in the corporate and academic space. A published academic who has become proficient in time management, team communication, customer experience, change management, hard work and fast learning. Experienced in writing and maintaining software from inception to realization.

#### **Education:**

3.0/4.0 GPA

**Bachelor of Science - Computer Science** w/Minor - General Business Administration East Carolina University Greenville, NC Fall 2017- Spring 2021

#### Associate of Science- General Education

College of the Albemarle Elizabeth City, NC 2016-2017 3.8/4.0 GPA

### Skills:

- Technology proficient (Software, Hardware, Bash/Shell, Citrix Workspace, VMware)
- **Programming Language proficient (Python, Java, C+, CSS/HTML5/SAS,** JavaScript, Kotlin, Swift)
- Database Creation and Management Experience (SQL, SQLite, MS Access)
- IoT/Virtualization Experience (Balena, Docker, Kubernetes, Splunk)
- Operating System proficient (Windows, Mac, Linux, Raspbian, BalenaOS)
- Microsoft Office proficient (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook)

#### **Work Experience:**

# Application Support & Development Internship

8 Week Program, – First Citizens Bank – Raleigh, NC

- o Determined software requirements for current banking needs
- Communicated requirements to various organizations within
- o Prepared timeline for development of various new software tools
- o Determined plans for the implementation of new software tools as well as facilitating change. (change management)

# Summer 2020

- Explored various Diversity and Inclusion initiatives
- Maintained current bank systems by providing outlet for correction of user-based exceptions
- Provided support for users of bank systems while also initiating clear follow-up communications to verify the success of support.

#### Academic Research - Multidisciplinary(ITCS/CS)

#### Dr. Ciprian Popoviciu - East Carolina University - Greenville, NC

- Designed, with several other students, a collection of Raspberry PI units mounted to Cisco WebEx technology to monitor network connectivity issues in the hopes of preventing/mitigating downtime.
- o Designed, implemented and managed teams website and web-based interfaces to provide a dashboard for user accessibility

https://pi-pirates-ecu.github.io/PI-Pirates-Site/

- Handled set-up of various physical and virtual labs.
- Utilized SAS, Linux, Balena, Raspbian, IPERF, Cisco AnyConnect software
- Utilized various open-source technologies, such as but not limited to, Docker, Phoronix Test Suite, BalenaOS

#### Freelance Software Developer (Mobile)

#### Greenville, NC

- o Communicated with customers regarding application features and timeline.
- Created development and iteration plan for logic/coding procedure
- **Documented procedures** for further development of product

January 2020 – Current

August 2019 – Current

- Managed **debugging** process, as well as, including plans for further iterations.
- Delivered product based on **communicated timelines**
- Maintained communication with customers to verify satisfaction

#### 10-12 Week Program, – **Dominion Energy** - Elizabeth City, NC

- Determined facility design for material, time and cost estimates for the construction and maintenance of residential electrical constructions; as well as relocation of distribution facilities for customers.
- Maintained communication with customers to provide service in a time efficient manner
- Inspected work request job sites, determine metering requirements and prepare sketches of property and service agreements.
- Prepared joint use notification CATV permits, underground agreements, revenue calculations, etc.
- Obtained right-of-way and easement agreements and highway/railroad permits.
- Assisted in service restoration in the field during outages.

# Customer Service & Main Office Assistant

January 2018 – January 2020

- Campus Recreation and Wellness Center East Carolina University Greenville, NC
  - Communicated with customers in person and via telephone and direct them to appropriate areas.
    Permitting access to the facility.
  - Used critical thinking skills to handle situations or conflicts that arise and communicate with other staff to resolve any issues.
  - Demonstrated knowledge of CRW programs & services including but not limited to: membership options/prices, CRW facilities/procedures, program areas, and professional staff area of responsibilities.
- Handled various payment methods for guest passes, late/lost fees, memberships, personal training sessions, aquatics activities, safety class registrations and lock sales throughout the day. Practice integrity while balancing the drawer at the beginning and end of shift.
- Worked weekends and holidays (even when classes are not in session) on a rotating basis.
- o Properly document lost and found items.

#### **Publications:**

Sawyer, Colby Lee. 2020. <u>Deploying a Network Management Overlay for Education Video Conferencing Services</u>. 2020 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference. https://www.asee.org/public/conferences/172/papers/29604/view

Sawyer, Colby Lee. 2020. <u>A Multidisciplinary Project: Deploying Edge Computing to Augment Endpoint Functionality</u>. 2020 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference. https://www.asee.org/public/conferences/172/papers/29638/view

Languages- English-Fluent, Spanish- Competent, ASL- Competent